Manuel A. Quintero Coronel

manuelquinterocoronel@gmail.com \cdot (+52) 1 56 11640566

Personal

I am a highly self-motivated student with a strong background in mathematics and statistics, with over three years working as a research assistant mainly in causal estimations using several statistical software. I am also interested in teaching: I have taught three courses at the graduate and undergraduate levels.

FIELDS OF INTEREST

- Mathematical Statistics Machine Learning, Deep Learning, and Causal Inference.
- Mathematical Economics Game Theory, DSGE models, and Microeconometrics.
- Pure Mathematics Functional Analysis, Partial Differential Equations, and Real Analysis.

EDUCATION

Cambridge University, Cambridge, UK

2022 - Present

MASt in Mathematical Statistics.

Instituto Tecnologico Autonomo de Mexico, CDMX, Mexico

2015 - 2020

Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics (Honours). GPA: 9.49 / 10.0 (Top 2.64%)

Instituto Tecnologico Autonomo de Mexico, CDMX, Mexico

2015 - 2020

Bachelor of Arts in Economics (Honours). GPA: 9.28 / 10.0 (Top 4.49%)

High School diploma from Canada and Mexico

2015

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant (MIT)

Mar 2021-Present

Supervisor: Fotini Christia, director of MIT Sociotechnical Systems Research Center (SSRC).

- Co-author of the paper: "Can Media Campaigns Empower Women Facing Gender-Based Violence amid COVID-19?" with Fotini Christia, Elizabeth Parker-Magyar (MIT), and Horacio Larreguy.
- Analyzed survey responses and conducted balance analysis, ran treatment and heterogeneous effects, made weights to mimic national samples, created inverse covariance indexes and z-scores, power-tests, Bayes-factors, ran LASSO models, and more.

Research Assistant (Harvard, ITAM)

Mar 2021-Present

- Supervisor: Horacio Larreguy.
 - Conducted the analysis of the paper: "Accountability under Polarization" for Jose Ramon Enriquez (Harvard), Horacio Larreguy, John Marshall (Columbia), and Alberto Simpser (ITAM).
 - Co-author of the paper "Can We Shield Citizens Against Misinformation Through Digital Literacy Training and Fact-checks?" with Antonella Bandiera (ITAM), John Marshall, and Horacio Larreguy.
 - Analyzed surveys responses for several projects: created balances tables, average treatment effects, heterogeneous effects, inverse covariance indexes, event studies, used quasi-experimental methods, implemented text-analysis techniques, machine learning techniques, matching statistical techniques, inverse propensity score weighting, multilevel Regression, and Post-stratification, and constructed Lee Bounds.

Graduate/Undergraduate Teacher Assistant (ITAM)

Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

Professor: Horacio Larreguy (ITAM)

Courses: Applied Research I (Masters of Applied Economics) and Economic Research Seminar (Economics department)

- I created tutorials for R, Stata, and LATEX.
- Taught experimental methods such as generalized Difference-in-difference, Instrumental Variables, and Regression Discontinuity.
- Supervised the research project of all students.
- Held office hours to answer specific questions about implementing quasi-experimental methods in R and Stata, as well as exporting the results to LATEX in a presentable manner.

Graduate Teacher Assistant (ITAM) Professor: Carlos Urrutia (ITAM) Jan 2021 - May 2021

Course: Dynamic Macroeconomics I (Master of Economic Theory)

• Taught laboratories in MATLAB to put class theory into practice: how to solve the Recursive Neoclassical Growth Model, DSGE models, and Bellman equations including models with heterogeneous agents.

Research Assistant (CIE-ITAM)

June 2020 - Dec 2020

Supervisor: Ignacio Lobato (ITAM)

• Assisted the professor in implementing his paper on non-invertible and non-causal ARMA models in MATLAB. I also assisted in grading the undergraduate course of Applied Macroeconometrics.

Research Assistant (CIDE-INEGI-ITAM)

June 2019 - Feb 2020

Supervisor: Victor Guerrero (ITAM)

- As a result of our work, INEGI formalized the creation of a business cycle dating committee for the Mexican
 economy in February 2021.
- I wrote a technical chapter on business cycle methodology and participated in the first international congress of business cycle dating committees from around the world.

Tutorship Program (ITAM)

Jan 2019 - June 2020

Member of the minor faculty of Statistics and Mathematics.

- Answered questions and gave advice on statistics and mathematics to any student at ITAM.
- Supervised departmental examinations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Licenses and certifications	
Data Science: R Basics by HarvardX (certificate)	June 2019
Data Science: Machine Learning by HarvardX (certificate)	July 2022
High-Dimensional Data Analysis by HarvardX (certificate)	July 2022
Using Python for Research by HarvardX (certificate)	Aug~2022
Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp (certificate)	$\mathrm{Aug}\ 2022$
Neural Networks and Deep Learning by DeepLearning.AI (certificate)	Sept 2022
Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter Tuning,	
Regularization and Optimization by DeepLearning.AI (certificate)	Sept 2022

Programming level

R / RStudio	0000
MATLAB	00000
Python	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$
Stata	$ \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet $
Java	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$
EViews	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$
C#	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$

Honors and awards

- Research Award: Honorable mention in Applied Mathematics (July 2022).
- Research Award: Honorable mention in Economics (Jun 2022).
- Sage Fellowship, Cornell University Rejected (Mar 2022).
- Undergraduate Student Scholarships at ITAM (Aug 2015 Aug 2018).
- Finalist at MIT Delta V Epic lab (2017).
- Business School Excellence Award ITAM (Aug 2015 Dec 2016).
- High School Valedictorian Instituto Chapultepec (2015).

Publications

• Bandiera Antonella, Horacio L. John M. Daniela P. and Manuel Q. 2022. "Can We Shield Citizens Against Misinformation Through Digital Literacy Training and Fact-checks?." Working paper.

- Christia Fotini, Horacio L., Eizabeth P., and Manuel Q. 2022. "Can Media Campaigns Empower Women Facing Gender-Based Violence amid COVID-19?" Working paper.
- Associate Researcher: Antón A. et al. 2020. "Propuesta para crear un comité de fechado de los ciclos económicos en México". INEGI. México. URL: http://internet.contenidos.inegi.org.mx/contenidos/productos/prod_serv/contenidos/espanol/bvinegi/productos/nueva_estruc/promo/GTDCFC_2020.pdf.